Derek Mahon Letters to Louis Asekoff, 1963-1988
Emory University
Letters to Louis Asekoff, 1963-1988
Mahon, Derek, 1941-
Manuscript Collection No. 1011
.25 linear ft. (1 box)
Letters and postcards from Irish poet Derek Mahon to Louis Asekoff, including drafts of poetry.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purcahse, 2005.
Restrictions on Access
Unrestricted access.
Biographical Note
Irish poet Derek Mahon met Louis Asekoff in the early 1960s while they were students at Trinity College in Dublin. Louis Asekoff (1939- ), poet and educator, currently coordinates the M.F.A. Program in Poetry at Brooklyn College. His poems have appeared in many magazines, including The New Yorker, Poetry, Tikkun, Salamagundi, Triquarterly, and The American Poetry Review. He has twice received The American Poetry Review Jerome Shestack Prize for Poetry. He has published two books of poetry, Dreams of a Work (1994) and North Star (1997) by Orchieses Press, Washington, D.C. He has received poetry fellowships from the National Endowment for the Arts, the New York Foundation for the Arts, and The Fund for Poetry.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of letters and postcards from Derek Mahon to Louis Asekoff from 1963-1988 and reflects their close literary and personal friendship which began when both were students at Trinity College, Dublin in the early sixties. Mahon's letters include references to poets and poetry, literary ambitions, teaching plans, reading tours, personal relationships, and visits with Asekoff. The collection also includes typscripts of several of Mahon's poems.
Arrangement Note
Arranged by record type.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Asekoff, L. S. (Louis S.), 1939-
Topical Terms
English authors--Irish authors--20th century.; Poets, Irish--20th century.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Poems.
Occupation
Poet.
Related Materials in This Repository
Derek Mahon papers and the Derek Mahon collection.
Container List
- Correspondence
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1963 (1 letter) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1964 (3 letters) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1965 (2 letters) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1967 (1 letters) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1969 (1 letter) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1971 (2 letters) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1973 (4 letters) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1974 (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1975 (3 letters, 1 postcard) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1977 (1 letter, 1 postcard) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1978 (2 letters, 2 postcards) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1979 (5 letters) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1980 (1 postcard) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1981 (2 letters, 3 postcards) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1982 (6 letters) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1983 (1 letter) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1984 (3 letters) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, 1986 (3 letters) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, September 12, 1987 (2 letters) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Mahon, Derek to Asekoff, February 24, 1988 (2 letters) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Writings by Derek Mahon
- "Breakfast at 'The Edge of the World,'" TS [See letter of April 24, 1964] (Box -, Folder -)
- "A Disused Shed in Co. Wexford (for J.G. Farrell)," TS (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "In Carrowdore Churchyard (at the gave of Louis MacNeice)," TS [See letter of June 23, 1965 (Box -, Folder -)
- "The Joycenterary Ode," [See letter of June 24, 1981] (Box -, Folder -)
- "La Condition Ouvrière," TS [See letter of June 7, 1964] (Box -, Folder -)
- "North City, South City," TS [See letter of June 7, 1964] (Box -, Folder -)
- "Sisyphus," TS [See letter of June 7, 1964] (Box -, Folder -)
- "The Snow Party," TS [See letter of May 1973] (Box -, Folder -)
- Printed material about Derek Mahon
- "A Parisian October Notebook," Fortnight, December 1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)